Ankit Joshi

Ahmedabad, Gujarat joshiankit810@gmail.com +91 9099609562

Experienced Recruiter with a demonstrated history of working in the recruitment companies and services industry. Skilled in recruitment, client servicing and sales. Strong client servicing professional graduated from Gujarat University.

Work Experience

Technical Recruiter

Aditi Consulting July 2019 to June 2020

- Responsible to work on assigned job requirements of fortune 500 company of USA.
- Review and understand the job requirements and explore all possible platforms (i.e Monster, Dice, CB, indeed, Linkedin)
- Identify the strong candidates in minimum time and screen them over a call. Verify skills and required qualification against the assigned job requirements.
- Negotiate rate with the candidate and get all required documents from the candidate.
- Responsible to submit the candidate on ATS as well as VMS after getting approval from account manager.
- Foster long term relationships with candidates.
- Report to the TL and Account manager on daily basis.

Recruiter

Infoseum IT OPC Pvt Ltd February 2019 to July 2019

- Handled recruitment process of bench sales department.
- Responsible to bring right candidate on bench with valid work authorization.
- Post training and placement program advertisement on all possible platform.
- Make calls and evaluate the candidate over a call and convince him to enrol in training and placement program.
- Make relation with candidate until they make a payment and register with us. Once registration done follow up on regular basis to update candidate for training program.
- Help candidate during registration process and responsible to forward all details to HR manager.
- Responsible to work under guidance of TL and Manager and report them on daily basis

Technical Recruiter

Ohm Systems

September 2018 to February 2019

- Work on assigned jobs and explore all possible platforms and methodologies to source candidates.
- Evaluate candidate during phone screening to verify skills and information mentioned on resume against the technical requirement of the job.
- Get all required information, documents and authorization before submitting to Account manager.

- Do follow-ups and get feedback from candidate post interview.
- Build long-term relations with candidates seeking employment according to job flow and future requirements.

Customer Service Representative

Motif Inc

April 2014 to April 2015

- · Responsible to handle backend and E-mail process of Affiliate Marketing Company.
- Help publisher to maintain their quality of their blogs or website.
- Evaluate the products according to their category.
- Handling critical issues and ensure the task completion with client satisfaction.
- Responsible to Complete the task within given time period and forward that report to the client and report to the TL or Manager.

Client Service Executive

Medusind Solutions

December 2011 to December 2012

- Handled the workers' compensation cases for US based insurance company.
- Analyze the fax which contains the details of patient's treatment and diagnosis.
- Initiate the case and create a claim according diagnosis and treatment.
- · Coordinate with provider office via Call to get missing information of patient.
- Responsible to completing the task within TAT and report to the team coach and manager.

Customer supports Officer

Mphasis an HP Company September 2008 to June 2011

- Handled the customers of entire Gujarat region.
- Answer the customer's calls regarding their issues with their prepaid connection.
- Perform the troubleshooting and resolve problem regarding GPRS or Internet.
- Achieve the target of quality and customer satisfaction with given time period.

Education

B.Com

Patel Arts & Commerce college

June 2008

Skills / IT Skills

• Talent acquistion, recruitment, client servicing, Business development